rtsthurnall.com 2011-01-25

# RTS Group - Privacy Policy

**Dated 05/11/2010**

**Who we are**    
RTS Life Science Limited ("RTS") is a company incorporated in England and a member of the Entologi Group.

RTS takes the privacy of all its customers and website users very seriously and takes great care with customer and user information. This Privacy Policy outlines how your personal information will be treated. 

We review our security and privacy policies periodically and you should check this page to see our most up to date policy (please see date at the top).   

**  
The information we collect  
**In order to provide you with our services, we may collect personal information about you from our website, telephone conversations, emails and written communications. We may for example, keep a record of your name, address, email address, telephone number and fax number.  We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we receive from third parties. Please let us know if any of your personal information changes or is inaccurate so that we may keep our records up to date. You can do this via your usual RTS contact person or see "How to contact us" below. 

**How we use your information**   
Any personal data relating to you will be used and recorded by us in accordance with applicable data protection legislation and this Privacy Policy. 

We may use your personal information to process any requests for information, goods or services you make. We will also use the information we hold to communicate with you, for example in the event that the information, goods or services you have requested are unavailable, for record keeping purposes, in aggregate, and therefore anonymously, for market research, to track activity on our website (see "Cookies" below) or to improve the quality of our service. We may also create an individual profile for you so that we can inform you of particular goods, services and events that may be of interest to you. This may be via email, post, telephone or fax.   

**  
Careers  
**If you send us your details with regards to an application for a position within RTS, we will store your information on our systems to enable us to provide and administer your request and for our general human resource management purposes, for subsequent retention for a limited period (for example, if you have been unsuccessful we may wish to keep your details for future positions - please note that you will receive an acknowledgement with details of when this may occur). 

We will use any of the contact information provided, such as your email address, telephone number(s) and postal address to contact you. We may supplement the information that you provide to us with information that we receive later or from third parties, for example references and this may form part of your application records and/or employment records if you are offered a position with us. As your application progresses through the recruitment process you will be informed separately of how your information will be used. 

**  
Cookies  
**New technologies help us to deliver customised visitor experiences. In particular, there is a technology called "cookies" which may be used by us to provide you with, for example, customised information from our website. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then store it on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and features, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. Depending on the type of cookie we use, cookies also allow us to make our website more user-friendly, for example, permanent cookies may allow and assist us when you request information to be downloaded from the website.  

If you wish, you can usually adjust your browser so that your computer does not accept cookies. If you do this, you will still be able to browse around the website but some functions may not be available. Alternatively you can adjust your browser to tell you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. How you adjust your browser to stop it accepting cookies or to notify you of them, will depend on the type of internet browser programme your computer uses. If your computer uses Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator, you will need to follow these instructions after clicking onto this link [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) (RTS is not responsible for the content of external websites. This link will open a new window.) Go to the heading "Manage Cookies". Click onto the option you prefer, either stopping cookies being installed, or notifying you of them. From the list provided, click onto the programme which your computer uses. If this is not shown on the list, click on the "help" heading on the bar at the top of this page, search for information on "cookies" - an explanation of how to delete cookies will appear, then follow these instructions.  

Please remember, cookies do not contain confidential information such as your home address, telephone number or credit card details. We do not exchange cookies with any third party websites or external data suppliers.

Your browser also generates other information, including which language the website is displayed in, and your Internet Protocol address ("IP address"). An IP address is a set of numbers which is assigned to your computer during a browsing session whenever you log on to the Internet via your internet service provider or your network (if you access the Internet from, for example, a computer at work). Your IP address is automatically logged by our servers and used to collect traffic data about visitors to our website. We do not use your IP address to identify you personally.  

**  
Disclosure of your information**   
We may share your personal information with other members of the Entologi Group each of which may use your information as described under the Section "How we use your Information" above.   

We may give information about you to the following, who may use it for the same purposes as set out above:

(a) to other members of the Entologi Group;  
(b) to employees and agents of the Entologi Group to administer any accounts, products and services provided to you by the Entologi Group now or in the future;  
(c) to anyone to whom we transfer or may transfer our rights and duties under our agreement with you (for example, a sale of the business);  
(d) if we have a duty to do so or if the law allows us to do so.

**  
Use of your information outside the European Union**   
Some of the members of the Entologi Group and other organisations to which we may disclose your information are situated outside of the European Union. In order to provide you with the information, products and services you require, we may need to transfer your information to these countries some of which do not protect privacy rights as extensively as in the United Kingdom. All Entologi companies, either in the UK or overseas, will however comply with this Privacy Policy. In requesting services and information where such a transfer is required, you consent to such a transfer for the purposes outline in this Privacy Policy.   

**  
Security  
**We take the security of your information seriously. We have security procedures in place to protect our customer database from loss and misuse, and only allow access to it when absolutely necessary, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of the personal information contained within it. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose on-line. You accept the inherent security risks of providing information and dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless this is due to our negligence or wilful default.  

**  
Links to other websites**

This website contains links to other websites. We are only responsible for the privacy practices on this website. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website that you visit.   

**  
What to do if you do not want to receive marketing information**   
You have the right to prevent marketing information being sent direct to you. If you prefer not to receive information from us, you can opt out of receiving further marketing by clicking the relevant boxes on the screen upon which you provide information or by writing to us by mail or email. Please note, however, that if you do opt out, we will be unable to keep you informed of new products, services or events that may be of interest. In addition, our email communications contain a facility to allow you to unsubscribe from receiving further emails.   

**  
Your rights to access your personal information**   
You have the right to know what personal information we hold about you. We may charge a small fee towards the cost of administering any request you make. The current fee (permitted by law) is £10.00. If you wish to exercise this right please see contact details below.  

**  
How to contact us**   
If you would like any further information or have any comments about our privacy policy or any other aspect of our website or service, please contact our Data Protection Compliance Officer by any of the methods shown below:   

Telephone: +44 161 777 2000   
Email: [gareth.bottrill@rts-group.com](mailto:gareth.bottrill@rts-group.com)  
Mail: Gareth Bottrill, IT Department, RTS Life Science, Northbank, Irlam, Manchester, M44 5AY United Kingdom   
Fax: +44 161 777 2095 

© RTS 2010. All Rights Reserved.
